# **Ravgeet Dhillon**

Software Engineer and Technical Content Writer with over 4+ years of experience who has worked with startups and open-source organizations across the globe. An individual with a teacher and student mindset.

Interested in a 100% remote role. Based in India (UTC+05:30).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer and Founder - RavSam, India

MAY 2020 - PRESENT

- Founded a Full Stack Development agency (ravsam.in) along with my father, and served clients with Web, Mobile, CMS, APIs, Automation, and DevOps services.
- Secured one year contract with <u>CloudAnswers</u> to provide Custom Software Development and Consultancy in Jamstack technologies (React.js, Next.js, Firebase).
- Worked on <u>Web</u> and <u>Flutter app</u> for Organic Farmers Connect which made the headlines in local newspapers.
- Key achievement: Learned about management, sales, and other aspects of running a small startup.

# Software Engineer & Technical Content Writer - Freelance, Remote

MAY 2018 - PRESENT

- Working on a contract basis with <u>Draft.dev</u> and <u>Honeybadger</u> to create, review and edit technical content related to React, Vue, Serverless, Python, and more.
- Writing detailed guides, howtos, tutorials for <u>ATA</u>, <u>CSS Tricks</u>, <u>Vonage</u>, <u>Twilio</u>, <u>Strapi</u>, and <u>many more</u> for showcasing the integration of their platforms with other tools and frameworks.
- Told by an editor, "You wrote so well, I'm tempted to use it on my own machine".
- Key achievement: Devised a model for networking and getting work opportunities.

# Full Stack Developer Intern - Techies Infotech, India

JANUARY 2020 - MAY 2020

- Designed websites based on Jamstack architecture which reduced the build times by 30% and increased PageSpeed scores to 90+.
- Architected Laravel websites for better code structure which decreased the feature development time by 20%.
- Key achievement: Got promoted to Intern Team Lead and lead a team of 4 interns in their assignments.

## Google Summer of Code Developer — GNOME Foundation, Remote

FEBRUARY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Redesigned the <u>GTK's official website</u> product and documentation using Bootstrap by keeping accessibility in mind.
- Migrated the legacy PHP codebase to Jekyll for Static Site Generation and implemented a Git-based CMS for non-technical contributors.
- Setup deployment of the website using Gitlab CI/CD to make the new changes live in under a couple of minutes.
- Key achievement: Made it is easy for non-technical individuals to contribute to an open-source project.

## **EDUCATION**

# B. Tech CSE — Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar (8.17/10.00 CGPA)

AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2020

- Served as the Technical Head of the Computer Engineering Student Society in 2019.
- Co-organized Polaris Tech Fest 2019 and various workshops related to Web Development and Open Source.

Phone: +91 9780221904 Email: <a href="mailto:ravgeetdhillon@gmail.com">ravgeetdhillon@gmail.com</a>

Website: ravgeet.in Blog: blog.ravgeet.in

Code: github.com/ravgeetdhillon
UI Design: dribbble.com/ravgeetdhillon
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ravgeetdhillon

#### **SKILLS**

#### Frontend:

React.js, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Jekyll, Redux, Vuex, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, UI/UX

#### Backend

Strapi, Laravel, Node.js, Express, Flask, Django, Rest APIs

## Languages:

Python, Javascript, Typescript, Dart, PHP

#### Mobile:

Flutter, Firebase, Provider

## Database:

MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RDBMS

## Hosting & DevOps:

Netlify, Vercel, Github Actions, Heroku, Gitlab CI/CD, Codemagic, VPS, Nginx

#### Addons:

Figma, Stripe, Slack, Notion, Markdown, Trello, Automation, CMS, Agile

## Development:

Linux Ubuntu, GitHub, VSCode, Prettier, Webpack, ESLint

### **PROJECTS**

## Metafold Store

A Strapi/Node.js powered E-Commerce website with <u>customer</u> and <u>admin</u> portals, build in Vue/Nuxt.js and deployed on Netlify and Hostinger VPS.

#### **Brandcares**

A Flutter app with Provider state management, connected to a Laravel powered backend, published on <u>Play Store</u> and <u>App Store</u>.

# **Notify Slack Github Action**

A <u>GitHub Action</u> to send a Slack Notification whenever a Github Action completes with success, warnings, or failure.

## **AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Curating a monthly, dev-related, and personal stories newsletter with 300+ subscribers.
- Developed and launched Notion Feeder and acquired 100+ customers in the first 80 days.
- Runners Up at Smart India Hackathon 2019 for creating a project that solves the traffic situation at toll booths in India.